wfubmc.edu 2001-10-23

# WFUBMC: Privacy Statement

**Wake Forest University Baptist Medical Center Privacy Statement**

**Overview**   
Wake Forest University Baptist Medical Center (WFUBMC) is recognized for our commitment to safeguarding consumer privacy on our web sites. We operate under the following set of strict privacy principles: 

The only information WFUBMC obtains about individual visitors to its web sites is that supplied voluntarily by visitors. 

In cases when WFUBMC may need personal information to provide visitors with customized content or to inform them about new features or services, visitors are explicitly asked for that information. 

Personally identifiable information provided by visitors (name, e-mail or home address, etc.) will not be disclosed to anyone unless visitors indicate that WFUBMC may do so. 

Personally identifiable information will not be shared at any time without the visitor's permission. WFUBMC employs strict security measures to safeguard online transactions; personal information is stored in a secured database and always sent via an encrypted Internet channel. 

The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices: 

**IP Addresses**   
An IP address is a number automatically assigned to your computer whenever you access the Internet. All computer identification on the Internet is conducted with IP addresses, which allow computers and servers to recognize and communicate with each other. WFUBMC collects IP addresses in order to conduct system administration and to conduct site analysis. If a visitor requests pages from WFUBMC, the WFUBMC servers enter the visitor's IP address into a log. To maintain visitor anonymity, WFUBMC does not associate IP addresses with records containing personal information. However, WFUBMC will use IP addresses to identify any visitors who refuse to comply with WFUBMC's in-house rules or access agreement, and to identify visitors who threaten our service, site, customers or others. 

**Cookies**   
Our site places a text file called a "cookie" in the browser files of your computer. Cookies are pieces of information that a web site transfers to an individual's hard disk for record keeping purposes. Our site uses cookies during your online session to deliver content specific to your interests. Cookies allow us to avoid showing you the same message repeatedly. Our cookies do not contain personal information. They do enable WFUBMC to relate your use of the site to information that you have specifically and knowingly provided to our site. 

**Registration**   
Our site's registration system requires users to give us contact information such as their name and e-mail address, and demographic information such as a ZIP code, sex, age or income level. The customer's contact information is used to contact the visitor when necessary. Users may choose (opt-in) to receive future mailings; see the choice/opt-in section below. Demographic and profile data is also collected at our site. We use this data to tailor the visitor's experience at our site, showing the visitor content that reflects their stated preferences 

**External Links**   
In order to provide visitors with greater value, WFUBMC may provide links to various third party web sites. However, even if a third-party affiliation exists between WFUBMC and that destination site, WFUBMC exercises no authority over linked sites, each of which maintains independent privacy and data collection policies and procedures. WFUBMC assumes no responsibility or liability for these independent methods or actions and is not responsible for the independent policies or procedures of destination sites. Similarly, WFUBMC cannot take responsibility for the privacy initiatives or the content of such web sites. These destination links are provided only for your convenience, and as such, you access them at your own risk. However, WFUBMC wishes to ensure the integrity of the WFUBMC web site and its destination links, so any comments pertaining to the WFUBMC web site or any sites accessed through WFUBMC links are greatly appreciated. 

**Surveys and Questionnaires**   
Our online surveys and questionnaires may ask visitors for contact and demographic information. The customer's contact information is used to contact the visitor when necessary. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-in section below. Demographic and profile data is also collected at our site but is only used for internal analysis for improving our web sites. 

**E-Commerce and E-Healthcare transactions**   
Some WFUBMC site features may use applications to collect data to facilitate an e-commerce or e-healthcare transaction. We will ask your explicit permission to transfer this data to the third party to facilitate this transaction. 

WFUBMC may store this information to verify the transaction for customer service and accounting reasons and may use this information to help personalize your experience on the WFUBMC site. 

**Public Forums**   
WFUBMC provides its users with chat rooms, forums, message boards and/or news groups. Please remember that any information disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information. 

**Security**   
The WFUBMC web site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. WFUBMC employs strict security measures to safeguard online transactions. 

**Children's Guidelines**   
Some sections of WFUBMC may be designed specifically for use by children under the age of 16. Contact information such as their name and e-mail address, and demographic information such as their ZIP code or age may be requested in those sections. In such cases, children will be notified that they should obtain permission from their parents before providing such information. 

WFUBMC does not disclose personally identifiable information about users under 16, whether or not an approval is obtained. Parents and those permitting minors to use the WFUBMC web site should be aware that any information voluntarily given by children in chat sessions, e-mail exchanges, BBS's, forums, etc., may be used by third parties to generate unsolicited mail or other contact with children. 

**Choice/Opt-In**   
Our site gives users the opportunity to opt-in to receive communications from us and our partners at the point where we request information about the visitor. 

This site also gives users the following options for removing their information from our database in order to stop receiving communications or our service. 

  1. You can send e-mail to [ webmaster@wfubmc.edu](mailto:webmaster@wfubmc.edu)
  2. You can send mail to the following postal address: E-Business Marketing Manager   
Wake Forest University Baptist Medical Center.   
Medical Center Blvd.   
Winston-Salem, NC 27157 
  3. You can call the following telephone number: (336) 716-6209 

**Correct/Update**   
This site gives users the following options for changing and modifying information previously provided: 

  1. e-mail [privacy@wfubmc.edu](mailto:privacy@wfubmc.edu)
  2. call the following telephone number: (336) 716-6209 

**Contacting the Web Site**   
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this web site, or your interaction with this web site, contact: 

Security and Privacy Officer   
WFUBMC, Inc.   
Medical Center Blvd.   
Winston-Salem, NC 27157   

**Website Access Agreement**   
Please see our Website Access Agreement for other terms and conditions governing your use of the WFUBMC web site.
